# KAREEM OLUSOLA

## **Professional Profile**

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A self-starter and highly motivated Senior "Azure" DevOps Engineer with over eight (8) years' experience in designing, maintaining and enhancing complex cloud environments through building engineering automation and productivity tools to streamline and scale applications in the production environment across the Azure public cloud platform. Highly keyed in keeping my skills up to date with the latest technologies. Overall IT experience is over eleven (11) years with over five (5) years leadership roles included. And I am open to relocation with sponsorship where necessary.

#### **TECHNOLOGY STACKS**

- DevOps Azure DevOps, Azure Al, Terraform, Docker, Traefik, Istio, Azure Kubernetes Service AKS, GitHub Actions, Azure ML, CodeQL, Azure Pipelines, Helm
- Compute Azure VM, EC2, EKS, App Service, Scale Sets, Azure Functions, Automation
- Databases Cosmos DB, Azure MySQL, Azure Maria DB, Azure SQL, Azure PostgreSQL
- Monitoring (CloudWatch, App Insights, Splunk, Datadog, Log analytics, Azure Monitor, Veracode, Dynatrace)
- Identity (Azure Active Directory, AAD Domain Services, AAD B2C, Azure Information Protection)
  - Management (Microsoft Azure Portal, Azure Advisor, Cloud Shell, Azure Backup, Azure Cost Management, Azure

- Policy, Azure Monitor, Azure Landing Zone
- Storage (File Storage, Archive Storage, Disk Storage, Blob Storage, Queue Storage, Data Box)
- Networking (VPC, Virtual Network, Application Gateway, Azure DNS, ExpressRoute, Load Balancer, VPN Gateway, Azure CDN, Traffic Manager

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Certified Kubernetes Administrator CKA
- Microsoft Certified: Azure DevOps Engineer Expert
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Administrator Associate
- HashiCorp Certified Terraform Associate

#### **INTERPERSONAL SKILLS HIGHLIGHTS**

- Self-starter, with refined ability to work with minimum or no supervision.
- Strong team collaboration. Work closely with team members to achieve goals.
- Solid, persuasive, and genuine communication, facilitation, and relationship-building skills.
- Excellent ability to establish and work to priorities while managing multiple work streams.
- Proven leadership abilities and very high attention to detail.

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

#### Senior Analyst Programmer • Hybrid • KPMG | May. 2023 - Oct. 2024

Deploy and manage Azure AI services (Cognitive service and Document intelligence) and Azure Machine learning - ML Studio Migrate Azure Pipelines to GitHub Actions and vise versa

Prepare Azure pipeline and GitHub Action workflow to sign enterprise software for distribution using Azure Sign Tool Deployed and managed Traefik as (Ingress Controller)

Prepare and manage Azure Kubernetes Cluster

Performed code reviews, evaluated implementations, and provided feedback for tool improvements.

Developed automation framework for public cloud infrastructure deployments

Worked with others to perform security reviews of hosting environments.

Integrated maven with GIT to manage and deploy project related tags.

Installed and configured GIT and communicating with the repositories in GITHUB and BITBUCKET.

Created dashboards in VSTS for CI/CD pipelines, Work items and bugs.

Resolved Merge Conflicts, configured triggers and queued new builds within the release pipeline.

Wrote PowerShell scripting for task automation and to schedule tasks.

Create and publish NuGet packages and maintain the NuGet infrastructure that several teams use at build time.

Played a key role in automating the deployments on Azure using GitHub, Terraform and Jenkins.

Used Kubernetes to orchestrate the deployment, scaling and management of Docker Containers.

Created a private cloud using Kubernetes that supports DEV, TEST, and PROD environments.

Write complex UI testing and unit tests for web applications and integrate the testing with ADO.

Manage Azure DevOps integration with Power Platforms

Design and manage IaC using Terraform

Deployed and managed Azure resources while leveraging Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment (CI/CD)

Performing end-to-end automation from Continuous Integration (CI) to Continuous Delivery using Azure DevOps Pipelines

Use Terraform for Automated infrastructure provisioning.

Maintained a single terraform TFSTATE file pointed to remote storage.

Use GitHub Actions for Static Code Analysis scanning.

Utilized automation tools such as Terraform, for automating deployments, monitoring, management, and incident response for the platforms.

Delivering advanced technical troubleshooting and problem-solving solutions for our clients' projects challenges.

## Senior. Azure DevOps Engineer • Remote • Digital Reliance – Datatech Services Ltd | UK Mar. 2021 – Apr. 2023

Prepare and manage Azure Kubernetes Cluster

Deploy Istio as (Ingress Controller) in separated namespaces.

Design and manage Azure resources while leveraging Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment (CI/CD) pipeline for fast-paced robust application development environment using Azure DevOps Pipelines

Automated infrastructure provisioning on Azure using Terraform.

Maintained a single terraform TFSTATE file pointed to remote storage.

Maintained high availability through fault tolerance, system standardization, and vigilant disaster recovery planning.

pipeline for a fast-paced robust application development environment.

Prepare Build and Release Pipelines for ASP.NET Core web application to Amazon ECS

Setup REPOS on Azure Git, merging code from develop branch to master branch and making it ready for deployment.

Automated Network Configuration changes like NSG rule updates and Load Balancing rule changes while leveraging Terraform Implemented Azure Networking solutions including Virtual Networks, gateways for point-to-site and site-to-site VPN connectivity, Load Balancers, and Application gateways.

Prepared capacity and architecture plan to create the Azure Cloud environment

Migrated on-premises resources into Azure Cloud using Azure Migrate

Designed enterprise solutions on the Microsoft cloud using modern cloud architectural patterns.

Managed the day-to-day administration and configurations of systems used to provide enterprise IAM (Identity and Access Management) and provisioning.

Application security events monitoring and pipeline security code scanning analysis.

Set up CI/CD pipelines for Microservices and integrated tools

Deployed Infrastructure into Azure using PowerShell, Azure CLI, Terraform, and ARM.

## DevOps & Systems Engineer • Hybrid • ADVANS Microfinance Network | Oyo State, NG Oct. 2019 – Feb. 2021

Setup repos on Azure Git, merging code from develop branch to master branch and make it ready for deployment.

Setups CI/CD pipelines on for .NET Core, Node Js, React Js, Angular applications etc.

Technical support in the end-to-end automation of PaaS deployments.

Terraform automation of web app configuration files.

Automation of containerized applications.

Automation of existing laaS resources via ARM Templates.

Infrastructure provisioning On-Prem & Monitoring networks and communicating with service providers. VMware Management Linux Server Administration SAS

Troubleshooting and resolving software and hardware related issues

Set up and maintenance of networking devices (servers, cisco solutions)

Installing and configuring computer hardware and software, and other peripheral devices.

Data Backup & Replications

Coordinate in-house Network Administrator

## Cloud Engineer • Hybrid • Tek Experts | Lagos NG Oct. 2018 - Sept. 2019

Support Microsoft Azure Customers, on behalf of Microsoft as an Agent.

Acts as the primary technical contact, delivering advanced technical troubleshooting and problem-solving solutions on authentication for azure clients.

Microsoft Office 365 deployment, Administration Support

Analyze Partner's project as a case study, research solutions, Do a re-pro and relay resolution back to Customers. Develop technical solutions for both internal and external knowledge base.

Troubleshoot complex problems and provide the best available solution or workaround within the agreed service levels. Liaising with Development & Field Teams to identify bugs and missing product functionality for future releases. Liaising with product management to identify and report bugs.

Support of "AAD Connect" to identify and re-mediate conflict between various Directories.

Support on Active Directory Domain Service and all configurations with protocols and NSGs.

Document solutions to known issues and consulting questions.

Document issues in a CRM system and defects in our engineering tracking tool.

Implement and support new and existing customers on azure active directory, migration of On-Premise environment to azure and identity protection.

Capture and share best-practice knowledge amongst azure technical and partner community's related to Microsoft Azure (Azure Active Directory, Application Identity Integration, Azure MFA, Azure KeyVault, AAD B2C, AAD B2B, Identity Protection management, Privileged Identity Management, Hybrid environment involving On-Premise and Cloud, Sign-in risk, Auditing, and Reporting).

Develop PowerShell scripts and ARM templates to automate the provisioning and deployment process Acted as a liaison between our Product Management and Engineering teams.

Collaborate with other employees for process improvement and suggestions.

## IT Solution Architect • Onsite • Microkernel Technologies Limited | Lagos, NG Mar. 2016 - Sep. 2018

On-premises and Cloud Identity integration with Azure AD

Datacenter equipment installations and management

Training IT staff to support an extensive list of clients.

Develop IT Managed Service division.

Oversees our Fleet/Network Operation Center.

Consult on IT-related services for ongoing projects.

Coordinate IT services with our Vendors and partners.

Manage Print Management Solutions (PMS) and Electronic Document/Content Management Solution (EDMS/ECMS) and its deployments.

Develops Technical Operational Management per projects.

Coordinate in-house Network Administrator.

General IT Projects Implementation.

Monthly Project Reporting & Training.

Facilitation and Technical Resource Management.

Oversee and manage the IT operations

Linux Server Administration

Microsoft Azure Identity Management

Microsoft Office 365 deployment and Management

## Team lead, Network Engineer • Onsite • Integrated Telecomm. Technologies | Lagos, NG Mar. 2014 - Feb. 2016

Cisco Router and Switch Configuration and Management

Incident escalations management

Data-center Installations (IDUs and ODUs) and Management

Deployment of Microwave Radio

Installation And Maintenance of Microwave radio

Technical Site Surveying for point to point and point to multi point installations

Project Management support

**Technical Site Surveying** 

Structured Cabling and Equipment racking

Network Monitoring using Wireshark

## Network Engineer • Onsite • Integrated Telecomm. Technologies | Lagos, NG May 2013 - Feb. 2014

Deployment of Microwave Radio
Installation And Maintenance of Microwave Link
Technical Site Surveying
Structured Cabling and Equipment racking
Network Equipment Monitoring

Basic Science Teacher • Onsite • National Youth Service Corps NYSC| Kebbi, NG Mar. 2012 - Feb. 2013

Teach Junior High school students basic science as a subject. Voluntarily trained Corps members on Computer installations and repairs.

#### **OTHER CERTIFICATIONS**

- Microsoft Certified Trainer
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate
- Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Foundations 2020 Certified Associate
- Agile Software Development
- Cisco Certified Network Associate Routing and Switching

#### **EDUCATION**

HND. Electrical and Electronics Engineering - Oct. 2011
 Yaba College of Technology, Lagos, NG